prana.com 2019-06-30

# Yoga, Travel, & Adventure Clothes With A Conscience | prAna

At prAna, we respect your privacy. We know it’s important to you and it’s important to us. 

Effective: November 7, 2018 

This privacy policy ("Policy") explains how your information is collected, used, and disclosed by prAna Living, LLC ("prAna"). Unless we otherwise indicate, this Policy applies to all information collected by prAna from any source, including information collected through our online services and activities, including this Website and our mobile applications (collectively, "Site"), and at retail locations. This Policy will not apply where we display or link to a different privacy policy. 

**Your Preferences:** If you receive our emails and catalogs and no longer wish to, just let us know at [pranapreference@prana.com](mailto:pranapreference@prana.com). You also may send requests about your contact preferences, changes to your information, or questions concerning our Policy or privacy practices by email or by writing us at the contact provided in the “Questions/Contact Us” section below. 

If you are a customer shipping internationally to a country in the European Union (EU) or European Economic Area (EEA), we try to restrict or minimize the information we collect from and about you. Nonetheless, we provide this Policy to identify all the ways in which we could collect, share, disclose, or otherwise manage your data when you interact with us, and explain your rights with respect to the limited data that we do collect. For residents of the EU/EEA, prAna is the data controller responsible for your personal data collected pursuant to this Policy. 

1\. Information We Collect 

We collect information from you in various ways, including through information you provide to us directly, information we or other third parties automatically collect, and information we receive from third parties. This includes data that identifies you personally whether directly (e.g., your name) or indirectly (e.g., information about your online use). 

A. Information You Provide 

We collect information you directly provide to us through our Site, in our stores and through your other interactions with us. This may include when you use our Site, register or create an online account with or through the Site, purchase products or services, request information from us, sign up for newsletters, catalogs, or our email list, use our service, enter into sweepstakes or other promotions, fill out a survey, request customer support, or otherwise communicate with or contact us. 

The information we collect from you generally falls into the following categories: 

  * **Contact Details:** We collect your contact information, such as name, postal address, email address, telephone or mobile number, fax number, or other similar identifiers.
  * **Financial Data:** If you make a purchase from us, we collect a credit/debit card number and related financial information (such as CVV, expiration date, and billing address), depending on the form of payment you choose.
  * **Transaction Details:** We may collect details about your purchases or other transactions with us, including, but not limited to, your transaction or purchase history, transaction channel, or the general location of the store you visit.
  * **Account Information:** You may choose to register for an account to make a purchase or use certain services. We collect information from you regarding your account registration, such as an email and password.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data:** We collect data concerning your preferences in receiving marketing, other targeted information from us, and your contact preferences.
  * **Other Data about You:** We may collect other information about you based on your interactions with us or that you choose to provide to us. For example, if you submit a product review you have the option to provide pictures or other information about yourself.

B. Information We Automatically Collect 

When you visit or interact with our Site, we may use a variety of technologies such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to automatically or passively collect certain information about your online activity. Please note that we automatically collect the following information about you: 

The information we collect from you generally falls into the following categories: 

  * **Computer or Device Information.** We may automatically collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address or other unique identifier or information from the computer, mobile device, tablet or other device you use to access the Site, including but not limited to your operating system, browser type and language, and information about the location of your device.  

  * **Usage Information.** We may collect information about your usage of and activity on our Site, including the date and time you visit the Site, the areas or pages of the Site that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing the Site, the number of times you return to the Site, items that are added to or remain in your virtual cart on the Site, other click-stream or site usage data, emails that you open, forward or click-through to our Site, and other sites that you may visit.

For information about your advertising choices and how to opt-out of location information collection, please see the “Your Rights, Choices and Opt-Outs” section below. 

C. Information Collected by Third Parties 

Third parties may also collect information about you on our Site through the use of technology. For example, third party analytics services may use cookies and web beacons to help us compile statistics about our Site and visitors to our Site. We receive assurances from those third party analytics services that they will not collect or access any information that directly identifies you on our Site. Other third parties may also collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you visit our Site, for example, to display prAna ads to you on third party websites and to deliver third party ads to our Site and others as described below. We also may use third party service providers to support our Site. 

This Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. 

D. Information Collected From Other Sources 

We may obtain information from other sources as follows: 

  * From other trusted third-party sources to update or supplement the information that you provide or that we collect automatically. This includes, for example, information from public databases or data aggregators (which may include your demographic information, previous purchases, shopping habits, lifestyle preferences, or other information to validate or supplement the information we collect from or about you).
  * From our partners and service providers (including, for example, business partners, analytics vendors, advertising networks and search information providers).

We may use this information to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect, personalize your experience on the Site, target our communications so that we can inform you of products, services or other offers that may be of interest to you, to measure ad quality and responses, and for internal business analysis or other business purposes. 

E. Combination of Information 

We may combine the information we collect from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Site, as well as information collected offline, across other computers or devices that you may use, and from third party sources. 

A. Use of Information by prAna 

We use information we collect for purposes described in this Policy or as disclosed to you in other ways including on our Site, in our stores, or in connection with our services. For example, we may use your information to: 

  * send you catalogs and other marketing;
  * provide and deliver products and services;
  * provide information we think may be of interest to you;
  * send you information related to products and services, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * invite you to participate in customer research opportunities, such as surveys and focus groups;
  * operate and improve our Site, services and products;
  * process and deliver contest entries and rewards;
  * manage and administer our community features and member programs and services;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * communicate with you about new contests, promotions and rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by prAna and our selected partners;
  * send you catalogs, information, newsletters, promotional materials and other offerings from prAna or on behalf of our selected partners and affiliates;
  * provide you with customized content, targeted offers, and advertising on the Site, via email, or across other websites, mobile applications, social media or online services you may use;
  * link or combine with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better service;
  * use your data in an anonymous, aggregated, or de-identified format for analytical, marketing, and demographic purposes; and
  * provide you with other services or for other purposes as disclosed at the time you provide your information or otherwise with your consent.

B. How prAna Uses Your Information for Interest-Based Advertising 

We and others may use information collected using third-party cookies, clear gifs, web beacons, or other technologies on our Site and in our emails to deliver prAna-branded advertising displayed to you on the Site, on other third-party websites, mobile apps, social media, or other online services and across the computers or devices you use. We and others also may use cookie information to know when you return to our website after visiting these third-party websites. We and others use this and other information about you to try to understand your interests and show you relevant advertising about products and services that may interest you. 

We also may display interest-based ads through digital advertising partners, like Facebook, Google, or other social media platforms or websites. For example, we may use these digital advertising partners to personalize ads you see on other websites or apps based on your shopping experience or other interactions with us. We do this only by sharing hashed information (which converts your email or phone number to a unique string of numbers and letters) that the social media platform then matches data against its own data for the limited purpose of serving advertisements. The matched and unmatched hashes are then deleted, and are not used for any other purpose. 

We also may use information we collect to deliver advertising that is targeted to individuals with similar interests. These tools allow us to create groups based on actual or assumed shared interests and/or factual characteristics based on anonymous and/or de-identified information to help us figure out what advertising may be most relevant. We also do this without having to share personal information with these third-party partners. 

For more information about this practice and your choices with respect to interest-based ads, see the “Your Rights, Choices and Opt-Outs” section below. 

C. Our Lawful Basis to Process EU/EEA Data 

For residents of the European Union or European Economic Area, we may use the information we collect from and about you for a variety of business purposes; in general to provide our services, provide you with the products you order, offer you this website, improve customer experience and engagement, and develop the services. We are committed to protecting and maintaining the privacy of your information, and will process your data only in accordance with applicable data protection law and this Policy. 

We will have a lawful basis for processing your data when: 

  * We need to process it in order to provide you with the products or services you request (e.g., to fulfill your order);
  * You have consented to such processing (e.g., to receive offers and promotional emails from us);
  * We have a legitimate interest for processing your data – e.g., for fraud prevention; network and information systems security; to provide the Site and ensure it functions properly; data analytics; enhancing, modifying, or improving our Site and services; identifying usage trends; determining the effectiveness of promotional campaigns; and/or
  * We are legally obliged to process it.

3\. Sharing of Information 

Certain sections of our Site are designed as open and public community areas for connecting and sharing with other people. When you sign up for or participate in these areas you will be asked to provide certain information that may be displayed publicly along with photos, stories, posts, product reviews and other information you choose to provide. We may also post or publish your information when you submit comments, stories, photos, and videos in connection with surveys, contests, sweepstakes, or promotions offered on the Site. 

We share your personal information with third parties as follows: 

  * with your consent, including if we notify you on the Site that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information or when you agree to our sharing of your information with other third parties for their own marketing purposes subject to their separate privacy policies;
  * with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us, including fulfilling orders or assisting us in advertising our products and services on third party websites;
  * we may share your name, address, email address, telephone number, data about your purchases, transaction details, computer or device information, usage information, or other similar information with our marketing partners or other third parties not affiliated with us. These third parties may (i) receive additional information about you from service providers and other third parties, and (ii) use the information collected from and about you (including the information received from us) to contact you via direct mail and/or email with selected offers they believe may be of interest to you, or to display ads that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to share this information with these companies, you may opt out as described in “Your Rights, Choices and Opt-Outs” section below.
  * if you choose to enter into one of our sweepstakes, contests, or other promotions (a “Promotion”) we may disclose your information to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, as required by law, as otherwise permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, or otherwise in accordance with the terms of this Policy;
  * to (a) comply with laws or respond to lawful requests and legal process, (b) to protect the rights and property of prAna, our agents, and others including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use or (c) in the good faith belief that disclosure is needed to respond to an emergency or protect the personal safety of any person; and
  * in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.

4\. Security of Your Personal Information 

prAna takes reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. While we make every effort to help ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee our security measures. 

5\. Your Rights, Choices, and Opt-Outs 

A. Cookies, Tracking Options and California Do Not Track Disclosures 

Certain parts of our Site require cookies. You may adjust your device or Internet browser settings to limit certain tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features of the Site or take full advantage of all of our offerings. Please refer to your device’s settings or your Internet browser’s “Help” section for more information on how to delete and/or disable your device or browser from receiving cookies or controlling your tracking preferences. 

While we and others give you choices described in this Policy, there are many ways Web browser signals and other similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking. Our system may not recognize Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers. We may use cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to link data collected across other computers or devices that you may use. 

B. Interest-Based Advertising Choices 

To understand your choices for receiving more relevant advertising provided on the Site or across other websites and online services, please review the information below: 

  * To learn more about such interest-based advertising, and to opt out of such collection and use for interest-based advertising by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) participating companies, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.
  * To opt out from the use of information about your online activities for interest-based advertising by Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) member companies, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.
  * To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.

On your mobile device, you may also adjust your privacy and advertising settings to control whether you want to receive more relevant advertising. 

C. Unsubscribing from our Marketing Communications 

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from prAna by following the instructions in those emails. If you choose to opt out of promotional emails, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations. 

You may send requests about your contact preferences, changes to your information or our Policy or privacy practices by email to [pranapreference@prana.com](mailto:pranapreference@prana.com) or by writing us at:

prAna Customer Service  
3209 Lionshead Avenue  
Carlsbad, CA, 92010

D. Opting Out of Marketing from Third Parties 

You may opt out of our sharing information with third parties for direct marketing purposes by contacting Customer Service at (866) 915-6457 or by email at [pranapreference@prana.com](mailto:pranapreference@prana.com) and providing your name and mailing address. Please include the statement “Opt-Out” in the subject field, so we can properly direct your inquiry. 

E. Opting Out of Location Collection 

You may opt out from allowing prAna to collect your geographic location by changing your location preferences on your mobile device or by following the standard uninstall process and deleting prAna's mobile application(s) from your device. 

F. EU/EEA Resident Rights 

For residents of the European Union or European Economic Area, you have a number of rights with respect to the personal data collected from or about you on the Site. This includes: (1) the right to request access to your data; (2) the right to rectify or correct your information (if we are processing it); (3) the right to erasure of your data, when there is no compelling reason for us to keep using it; (4) the right to restrict further processing of your personal data; (5) the right to object to certain types of processing of your personal data; (6) in some instances, the right to request that prAna export your personal data, in a structured, commonly used, and machine readable format, and transmit to another controller; (7) the right to withdraw consent, at any time, if you have given your consent to anything that we do with your personal data; and (8) the right to lodge a complaint about the way we handle or process your personal data with your national data protection regulator. 

If you are a resident of the EU or EEA and wish to exercise any of these rights with regards to your personal information that we hold, please contact us via email at [pranapreference@prana.com](mailto:pranapreference@prana.com). Further information and advice about your rights can be obtained from the data protection regulator in your country. Pursuant to applicable data protection law, we may be entitled to refuse to act on the request. 

6\. Data Storage and International Transfers 

This website is operated by prAna Living, LLC, a company which is headquartered in the United States of America. To provide you with this website and the goods and services you order, your data may be processed by prAna Living, LLC, its affiliates, and its service providers, who may be located in countries (including the USA) other than your country of residence. These countries may have data protection laws that are different than the laws in your country of residence, but prAna will protect your personal information in accordance with applicable data protection law and this Policy at all times. 

In particular, where we transfer your information outside the EU or EEA, we make sure that any such transfers are conducted in accordance with applicable laws and using adequate and appropriate safeguards, including transferring to companies that are Privacy Shield certified or using approved standard EU Model Clauses. To find out more about how we safeguard your information (including obtaining a copy of such safeguards) in relation to transfers outside the EU or EEA, please contact us as directed in the “Questions/Contact Us” section below. 

7\. International Customer Privacy 

A. International Shipping Orders 

For international shipping orders, prAna uses the services of Borderfree, Inc. ("Borderfree"). We have contracted with Borderfree to ensure that they will process your information consistent with this Policy. When we identify that your order is one that will be shipped internationally, we work with Borderfree to complete your order. Borderfree generally will collect and process your information, and you will be presented with Borderfree's terms and conditions to which you must agree in order to receive the product(s) you ordered. 

Once you place your order, you may see box you can check if you would like to receive information from prAna regarding offers and promotions that may be available from time to time. If the box is checked, Borderfree will share your information with us, and we will protect and use your information in accordance with this Policy. 

For international customers, you can direct any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of your information by sending us an email or writing us as directed in the “Questions/Contact Us” section below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Policy. 

For residents of the EU or EEA, we will keep your personal data for as long as we need it for the purpose for which it is being processed. For example, we will retain your information for as long as you would like us to send you promotional offers or as needed to provide you with our goods or services; and after that, we will keep the personal data for a period which enables us to handle or respond to any complaints, queries or concerns relating to your account. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

8\. Your California Privacy Rights 

If you are a California resident, you may opt-out of our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To opt out, please contact us at [pranapreference@prana.com](mailto:pranapreference@prana.com). You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information. 

Non-affiliated third parties are independent from prAna and if you wish to receive information about your disclosure choices or stop communications from such third parties, you will need to contact those non-affiliated third parties directly. 

9\. Third-Party Content, Links, and Plug-Ins 

The Site may have links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the practices of such sites. 

The Site may also offer you the ability to interact with social plugins from social media sites, which may allow us and/or the social media site to receive data from or about you. In some cases, we may know that you clicked on a social plugin, such as a Twitter Follow button, or receive other information from the social media sites. Similarly, if you have previously provided personal information to a third-party operating a plug-in on this Site, then such third-party may recognize you on this Site. Your use of social network plugins is subject to each social media site’s privacy policy, which may be different from ours, so please read these policies carefully to understand their policies and your options. As with linked sites, we have no control over the information that is collected, stored, or used by social network plugins, and are not responsible for the practices of such sites. 

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Site to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen. If prAna learns that a child under the age of thirteen has provided personally identifiable information to the Site, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from our files. 

11\. Changes To This Policy 

prAna may change this Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the "Last Updated" date above. 

If you have any questions about this Policy or our privacy practices, you may email us at [pranapreference@prana.com](mailto:pranapreference@prana.com) or write us at: 

prAna Customer Service  
3209 Lionshead Avenue  
Carlsbad, CA, 92010
